# Sahar Alhabsi



sahar96alhabsi@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/saharalhabsi



98003011



https://saharalhabsi.github.io/sa7ar/

## **Summary**

Experienced Software Developer with a history of working in the Program Development industry. Skilled in Mobile Applications, Program Development, Web Development, and Artificial Intelligence. Bachelor's degree focused in Software Development. Interested in technology and 4Industrial Revolution(4IR).

## **Experience**

### Software Developer

DataBoat OM

Jun 2021 - Present (2 years)

- Develop Laravel framework projects.
- Configure Codeigniter project.
- Built Ionic Project and Angular.js
- Develop Asp.Net web api.

### Software Engineer Intern

DataBoat OM

Mar 2021 - May 2021 (3 months)

- Researching, designing, implementing, and managing software programs.
- Testing and evaluating new programs.
- Identifying areas for modification in existing programs and subsequently developing these modifications
- Maintaining and upgrading existing systems.
- Prepare reports by collecting, analyzing and summarizing information,
- Maintain quality service by establishing and enforcing organization standards.

# Mobile Application Developer

**GSTC Space and Technology** 

May 2020 - Aug 2020 (4 months)

- Developing mobile application in hybrid:-
- o ionic and angular as frontend
- Design the mobile app.
- Collecting and entering data into the application.

# 🌉 Hybrid Mobile Application-Training

Information Technology Authority - Oman

Mar 2020 - Jul 2020 (5 months)

Train to develop hybrid mobile applications using html, css,typescript, angular and ionic framework

# Sanad Service Center

#### Sanad Service Cente

Dec 2019 - Mar 2020 (4 months)

Customer service for each of

- The Ministry of Manpower in submitting requests for submission and updating the workers' record and approving or canceling work contracts.
- The Ministry of Regional Municipalities and Water Resources in submitting requests for construction services, which includes and health services
- Oman Chamber of Commerce and Industry in renewing the affiliation certificate.
- A portal to invest easily in updating and adding activities and delegates and extracting the commercial register.
- The Royal Oman Police is applying for an electronic visa and an online application for visas.



#### 🎥 Introduction to IOS Application - Training

Information Technology Authority - Oman

Jan 2019 - Jan 2019 (1 month)

- Learning basic level to middle about building IOS applications in Xcode
- Swift programming.
- Developing simple app like :calculator, table view ZooApp



### Training in IT department

Ministry of Education of Oman

Jun 2018 - Jul 2018 (2 months)

- 1- Train in Technical support:
- -Knowing the component of computer.
- -Solving some problem which happen of computer like beeb sound ,network issue.
- 2- Doing exchange server and designed a website.

### IT Training

University of Technology and Applied Sciences

Oct 2017 - Nov 2017 (2 months)

- 1- Formatting computer system and download windows server and windows operating system.
- 2- Computer components.
- 3-Setting router and modem.
- 4-Sharing file and printing through local network.

#### **Education**

#### University of Technology and Applied Sciences

Bachelor's degree, Software development 2014 - 2019

#### **Skills**

MySQL • PHP • Python (Programming Language) • Mobile Applications • Web Development • Information Technology • Artificial Intelligence (AI) • Machine Learning • Android Development • ASP.NET MVC